<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Samson Gama</title><link>https://samsongama.com/</link><description>Recent content on Samson Gama</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samsongama.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastercard Verifeye</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-06-14-mastercard-verifeye/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-06-14-mastercard-verifeye/</guid><description>Verifeye was a POC done during #innovationweek with the goal of coming up with new ideas to solve existing problems. It is not an official Mastercard project, but it came to fruition during the #innovationweek competition.
The purpose of Verifeye was simple, dynamic biometrics for authentication, verification and user engagement:
Verify a user based on their approximate age, gender, and other facial features in addition to the CVV code of their credit card Use sentiment analysis to determine and record how the user feels about the purchase and the flow of the transaction Initial Screen For the purposes of simple visualization, the following image will have all the debug information printed on screen for your benefit</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration/Deployment</title><link>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-08-cicd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-08-cicd/</guid><description>Everytime a developer changes some code, he commits it and pushes it upstream to the repository. From there, they can create a PR for other developers to review the code. After the PR is approved, the code can be merged into develop or master branches. Without continous integration and deployment, the new code has to be manually verified for integration and manually deployed. This is generally a tedious, repeated task.</description></item><item><title>Notifications</title><link>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-04-notifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-04-notifications/</guid><description>Notifications make monitoring useful.
When looking at it from a passive monitoring perspective using Prometheus, Alertmanager is a great service to leverage as it can hook into Slack, PagerDuty, or even SMS.
Other times you may want to know when a client registers on your SaaS product, or when a client is attempting to leave. This is known as Application Performance Monitoring. One example in my trading bot is that whenever the bot executes a trade or a stoploss is invoked, send me a slack message.</description></item><item><title>Passive Monitoring</title><link>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-01-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-06-01-monitoring/</guid><description>Monitoring is a big topic. I can attempt to simplify it into a few categories.
Passive Infrastructure Monitoring: Track CPU, Memory, Load, Uptime, Network, etc Log shipping: This is where your services stream their logs and you set alerts or metrics on certain patterns Active Monitoring: Ping your servers on a timer for aliveness/health, or a full verification of an API endpoint and its response Application Performance Monitoring: Metrics through code injection/addition to view application metrics The one I want to discuss today is passive monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Millions of Inserts | The ideal database?</title><link>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-03-01-insertingdata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/post/2018-03-01-insertingdata/</guid><description>Disclaimer: I haven&amp;rsquo;t ran any benchmarks or ran any of these databases in HA mode for proof of concepts but this was my experience with trying to work with lots of data for my HFT Trading Bot.
The Data: (all indexed on time)
1 minute candle: {timestamp, instrument, high, low, open close, volume, trades}, 1 inserts per minute Individual trade: {timestamp, instrument, price, side, type}, 0-2000 inserts per minute Individual order: {timestamp, instrument, price, side, type, status}, 0-5000 inserts per minute Note: There will exist one collection/database per exchange as certain exchanges provide more valuable information than others.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://samsongama.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 11:16:18 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/contact/</guid><description/></item><item><title>HFT Bitcoin Bot</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-11-01-hft-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-11-01-hft-bot/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Bitcoin since 2011. I never really believed in it as a currency back then because I thought there was no way soverign nations would allow such a currency to circumvent their own. Additionally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it had any intrinsic value. Fast forward three years, Bitcoin hits $1000. People call it overvalued. They offer their expert layman advice and tell everyone they know not to buy Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Absolute Software</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-06-05-absolute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-06-05-absolute/</guid><description>I was brought on as a backend developer to design and create components of a massive data processing pipeline. However, my skills and understanding of DevOps allowed me to take on more responsibilities and make better decisions for the data pipeline.
One of my greatest accomplishments at Absolute has been changing the inbound data pipeline to leverage Kubernetes amazing autoscaling and Golang impressive asynchronous capabilities to increase the throughput of the pipeline by 2000% while reducing memory consumption by 90%.</description></item><item><title>Ansible, why didn't I use this sooner</title><link>https://samsongama.com/post/2017-07-01-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/post/2017-07-01-ansible/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Linux since 2008. Back then, I mostly used a spare machine to run FreeNAS, Apache, MySQL, Python to host a static or Wordpress website. Then as I got more invested with projects running on Linux, I started to set up VPSes to start hosting online in 2011. Everytime, it was the same process. Login as root, set up new user, disable root, set up PKA, enable firewall&amp;hellip; etcetc.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning &amp; NLP Capstone</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-01-01-ubc-capstone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-01-01-ubc-capstone/</guid><description>For my final year project at UBC, I built a SaaS service which will infer context from some textual or image input in order to better target advertisment parameters.
The service will infer the time window, place, and sentiment from the input and then suggest advertisement parameters.
In order to do so, we leveraged multiple third parties such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon Rekognition, IBM Watson and more. Additionally, we built our own models and use libraries such as Google’s Tensorflow and Syntaxnet to further process the inputs.</description></item><item><title>Kudolife</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-09-01-kudolife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-09-01-kudolife/</guid><description>Between January to August 2016, I was a full-stack developer on the Kudolife App at Prizm Media. During my time, I published multiple iOS and Android releases. Optimized the server stack for the backend in addition to creating new APIs and removing bugs that were revealed from testing. The result was an on average across the platform a 50% reduction in response time and a much more fluid user experience.</description></item><item><title>Ericsson Openstack</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-01-01-ericsson-openstack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-01-01-ericsson-openstack/</guid><description>• Debugged and assisted in the development of an OpenStack Neutron plugin for managing virtual Ericsson routers
• Enhanced the team’s development and testing process by writing scripts which tested various commands for different scenarios and environments
• Investigated and implemented secure methods of communication between multiple VMs without reconfiguring Linux interfaces during runtime
• Used Docker within OpenStack to debug containers and to automate tests
Find out more about the project here: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Kinect SVM</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-06-01-kinect-svm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-06-01-kinect-svm/</guid><description>• Used SVMs to detect shapes drawn on a piece of paper which corresponded to a task on a host machine
• Determined if a user was pressing a drawn button using the depth data from the Kinect
• Implemented multithreading in order to maintain 1080P video capture and SVM detection simultaneously at 30FPS
• Created a utility application which allowed us to rapidly train SVMs with new shapes for different OS tasks</description></item><item><title>Endless-Sphere</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-02-01-endless-sphere/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-02-01-endless-sphere/</guid><description>During my time as one of the administrators of Endless-Sphere, I have accomplished the following:
migrated the forum from a rather expensive and unreliable VPS to AWS reduced costs and sysadmin time by automating backups and using some of AWS&amp;rsquo;s managed services introduced SSL certificates by LetsEncrypt which cut costs even more You can find me on the forum as user gammaray!
With nearly 25,000 users, Endless-Sphere is possibly the biggest Electric Vehicle Enthusiasts Forum in the world.</description></item><item><title>Boardcast for Android</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-12-01-boardcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-12-01-boardcast/</guid><description>• Design and development of a peer-to-peer collaborative whiteboarding application following the latest Android development guidelines and best practices
• Implemented a hardware accelerated multitouch drawing layer capable of discretizing gestures for manipulation of the canvas
• Designed a custom socket and messaging layer for seamless low-latency, peer-to-peer communication between an arbitrary number of connected devices
• Created a connection scheme that would allow an arbitrary number of devices to connect using either NFC and Wifi Direct or a local WiFi network with DNS service discovery</description></item><item><title>UberNios</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-10-31-ubernios/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-10-31-ubernios/</guid><description>• Created a 2D arcade game in C running on a custom embedded system implemented on the Altera DE2 FPGA
• Designed the embedded system with a NIOS II processor on the Altera DE2 FPGA using VHDL and Verilog
• Simulated a 3D perspective using image manipulation by resizing and shifting images as the game progressed
• Achieved delay free audio playback by using hardware timers and interrupts
• Achieved a high frame rate by only redrawing pixels that changed between frames in front of a static background</description></item><item><title>Fleetaware</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-10-01-fleetaware/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-10-01-fleetaware/</guid><description>FleetAware As first time Hackathon attendees, our team wanted to develop something that could not only help improve the way a demographic lives their lives or does their work, but also potentially improve on a piece of technology that already exists, adding functionality and configuring existing APIs to further enhance the overall impact the code can make.
After speaking with representatives at the Mojio booth, we realized that the technology they created could be extended to enable management of large vehicle fleets.</description></item><item><title>Electric Bicycle</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-07-01-electric-bicycle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-07-01-electric-bicycle/</guid><description>Electric Bicycle Built with the help from Justin and Robbie over at Grin Technologies…. Note: Old Picture Frame: Montague (so I think, bought on CL) Motor: Nine Continent 2807 Battery: AllCell Tech 36V 11Ah Controller: ASI BAC-350 Headlight: Cycle Lumenator Taillight: Rear Red Electrolight Display: Cycle Analyst Logger: Custom Bluetooth Module (HC-05) Other ebikes.ca/Grin Technologies accessories.</description></item><item><title>EV Trip Analyzer</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-06-01-ev-trip-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-06-01-ev-trip-analyzer/</guid><description>The Trip Analyzer is a web application for analyzing analog and digital data recorded on electric bicycles for the purpose of scruntizing trip data which allows for further analysis. I developed this application during my Engineering Co-op work term at Grin Technologies (more commonly known as ebikes.ca) and was the lead software developer on this project since it has been in motion.
The Trip Analyzer parses and extrapolates data which is outputted by the Cycle Analyst during a users trip and allows the user to view their speed, power consumption, efficiency and elevation data plotted against various axis.</description></item><item><title>Spoke Calculator</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-05-01-spoke-calculator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-05-01-spoke-calculator/</guid><description>The Spoke Calculator is a multi-purpose tool which allows users to both visualize their wheel build and determine the length of spokes necessary for the build. This is an important calculation as the tolerances for wheel builds are very low.
The Spoke Calculator was made with HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript with extensive use of the Javascript Vector Graphics library JSGL.
Try it out here: http://www.</description></item><item><title>Electromagnetic Tetherbot</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-04-01-electromagnetic-tetherbot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-04-01-electromagnetic-tetherbot/</guid><description>For project two of EECE 281, my teammates and I built a Electromagnetic Tetherbot which would follow a electromagnetic signal generated by a transmitter and various other functions mentioned in the embedded video. Both the transmitter and receiver were programmed in C, however the Android Application was programmed in Java. We addressed the project requirements by creating an effective solution with an Android application which allowed users to send commands with a tablet or a phone.</description></item><item><title>Heart Rate Monitor</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-03-01-heart-rate-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-03-01-heart-rate-monitor/</guid><description>For this module, I designed, built, programmed, and tested a microcontroller-based photoelectric heart rate monitor. This type of heart rate monitors are attached to a patients’ finger to measure their heart rate in beats-per-minute (BPM). The device I built is based on a non-invasive photo transmitter/receiver pair sensor which detects small variations of blood flow in the fingers due to the heart pumping action. After filtering and amplifying such variations, a microcontroller useable signal can be generated.</description></item><item><title>Oven Controller</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-02-01-over-controller/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-02-01-over-controller/</guid><description>I worked in a group of six to build a reflow soldering oven controller in assembly for the DE2-8052 microcontroller and a Java application which allowed users to set their reflow parameters using the FPGA or an Android device of their choice. We addressed the project requirements by creating an effective solution in assembly and added the ability to transmit data over serial to a Java application which created a strip chart for the current oven temperature and additionally hosted the SQLite database necessary for the integration of our Android application.</description></item><item><title>Veazey Scholars</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2013-08-01-veazey-scholars/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2013-08-01-veazey-scholars/</guid><description>I made this website alongside my friend Albert Hynek for Borden Ladner Gervais LLP and the Veazey Scholarship Foundation. I am luckily one of the recipients of the Tom and Phyllis Veazey Scholarship for which I am very thankful for.
Visit this site: http://veazeyscholars.</description></item><item><title>Elsie Roy iPad Project</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2012-01-01-er-ipad-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2012-01-01-er-ipad-project/</guid><description>The Elsie Roy iPad project (2010 – 2013) was a great success in that it both taught us a lot about mobile device deployment as well as giving other schools more incentive to invest in mobile technology to use in the classroom.
What is personalized learning?
The focus of personalized learning is to provide each individual a pathway to explore areas of learning that are based on personal passions. It means providing a more personalized learning experience centred on each person’s engagement, self-direction and self-management.</description></item><item><title>King George Website</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2010-10-01-kg-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2010-10-01-kg-website/</guid><description>This is the product of several like-minded students coming together to make a new school website. Being one of the five webmasters of this site, I have been part of this website since the conception of the idea to make a new school website back in 2010. Due to other commitments at the time, the website only went live in August 2011. Since then it has been in integral part of the school’s culture used for every major event.</description></item><item><title>Green Screen Projects</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2010-09-01-green-screen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2010-09-01-green-screen/</guid><description>For every video project assigned in high school, my friend Albert Hynek and I would often make videos that require the use of a green screen. He was always responsible for filming and editing while I was always responsible for the manipulation of the clips. The software I used to manipulate the green screens within the clips was Adobe After Effects CS5/6.
On a sidenote, most of our video projects always seemed to carry a Star Trek theme as identifiable by the screenshot on the right.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/</guid><description>A mashup of my worthy projects. More to come for sure.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://samsongama.com/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/resume/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Samson Gama</title><link>https://samsongama.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/about/</guid><description>Mission Statement Fueled by motivation, obsessed with perfection, I attempt to innovate the present day by providing society a glimpse of things to come.
Professional There are many things to talk about in terms of my professional development. At this time, while browsing my website I don&amp;rsquo;t want to direct your attention to anything in particular, but rather let you see my accomplishments. I get things done. I like to find things that are lacking in current implementations if any and make them better.</description></item></channel></rss>