<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>. on Samson Gama</title><link>https://samsongama.com/tags/</link><description>Recent content in . on Samson Gama</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samsongama.com/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ctf.samsongama.com</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-12-23-ctfsamsongamacom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-12-23-ctfsamsongamacom/</guid><description>CTF Writeups
ctf.samsongama.com
CTF</description></item><item><title>TrendMicroCTF 2019 Finalist</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-11-23-trendmicroctf2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-11-23-trendmicroctf2019/</guid><description>I am proud to announce that we (Maple Bacon) finished 12th place in the TrendMicroCTF 2019 Finals in Tokyo. A modest finish but I believe it is the first time Canada has been represented in the finals of an international CTF competition.
We plan to be back next year with more momentum.
Team</description></item><item><title>Mastercard Verifeye</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-06-14-mastercard-verifeye/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2019-06-14-mastercard-verifeye/</guid><description>Verifeye was a POC done during #innovationweek with the goal of coming up with new ideas to solve existing problems. It is not an official Mastercard project, but it came to fruition during the #innovationweek competition.
The purpose of Verifeye was simple, dynamic biometrics for authentication, verification and user engagement:
Verify a user based on their approximate age, gender, and other facial features in addition to the CVV code of their credit card Use sentiment analysis to determine and record how the user feels about the purchase and the flow of the transaction Initial Screen For the purposes of simple visualization, the following image will have all the debug information printed on screen for your benefit</description></item><item><title>HFT Bitcoin Bot</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-11-01-hft-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-11-01-hft-bot/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been following Bitcoin since 2011. I never really believed in it as a currency back then because I thought there was no way soverign nations would allow such a currency to circumvent their own. Additionally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it had any intrinsic value. Fast forward three years, Bitcoin hits $1000. People call it overvalued. They offer their expert layman advice and tell everyone they know not to buy Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Absolute Software</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-06-05-absolute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-06-05-absolute/</guid><description>I was brought on as a backend developer to design and create components of a massive data processing pipeline. However, my skills and understanding of DevOps allowed me to take on more responsibilities and make better decisions for the data pipeline.
One of my greatest accomplishments at Absolute has been changing the inbound data pipeline to leverage Kubernetes amazing autoscaling and Golang impressive asynchronous capabilities to increase the throughput of the pipeline by 2000% while reducing memory consumption by 90%.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning &amp; NLP Capstone</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-01-01-ubc-capstone/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2017-01-01-ubc-capstone/</guid><description>For my final year project at UBC, I built a SaaS service which will infer context from some textual or image input in order to better target advertisment parameters.
The service will infer the time window, place, and sentiment from the input and then suggest advertisement parameters.
In order to do so, we leveraged multiple third parties such as Microsoft Azure, Amazon Rekognition, IBM Watson and more. Additionally, we built our own models and use libraries such as Google’s Tensorflow and Syntaxnet to further process the inputs.</description></item><item><title>Kudolife</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-09-01-kudolife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-09-01-kudolife/</guid><description>Between January to August 2016, I was a full-stack developer on the Kudolife App at Prizm Media. During my time, I published multiple iOS and Android releases. Optimized the server stack for the backend in addition to creating new APIs and removing bugs that were revealed from testing. The result was an on average across the platform a 50% reduction in response time and a much more fluid user experience.</description></item><item><title>Ericsson Openstack</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-01-01-ericsson-openstack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2016-01-01-ericsson-openstack/</guid><description>• Debugged and assisted in the development of an OpenStack Neutron plugin for managing virtual Ericsson routers
• Enhanced the team’s development and testing process by writing scripts which tested various commands for different scenarios and environments
• Investigated and implemented secure methods of communication between multiple VMs without reconfiguring Linux interfaces during runtime
• Used Docker within OpenStack to debug containers and to automate tests
Find out more about the project here: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Kinect SVM</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-06-01-kinect-svm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-06-01-kinect-svm/</guid><description>• Used SVMs to detect shapes drawn on a piece of paper which corresponded to a task on a host machine
• Determined if a user was pressing a drawn button using the depth data from the Kinect
• Implemented multithreading in order to maintain 1080P video capture and SVM detection simultaneously at 30FPS
• Created a utility application which allowed us to rapidly train SVMs with new shapes for different OS tasks</description></item><item><title>Endless-Sphere</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-02-01-endless-sphere/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2015-02-01-endless-sphere/</guid><description>During my time as one of the administrators of Endless-Sphere, I have accomplished the following:
migrated the forum from a rather expensive and unreliable VPS to AWS reduced costs and sysadmin time by automating backups and using some of AWS&amp;rsquo;s managed services introduced SSL certificates by LetsEncrypt which cut costs even more You can find me on the forum as user gammaray!
With nearly 25,000 users, Endless-Sphere is possibly the biggest Electric Vehicle Enthusiasts Forum in the world.</description></item><item><title>Boardcast for Android</title><link>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-12-01-boardcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samsongama.com/portfolio/2014-12-01-boardcast/</guid><description>• Design and development of a peer-to-peer collaborative whiteboarding application following the latest Android development guidelines and best practices
• Implemented a hardware accelerated multitouch drawing layer capable of discretizing gestures for manipulation of the canvas
• Designed a custom socket and messaging layer for seamless low-latency, peer-to-peer communication between an arbitrary number of connected devices
• Created a connection scheme that would allow an arbitrary number of devices to connect using either NFC and Wifi Direct or a local WiFi network with DNS service discovery</description></item></channel></rss>